Josh Davies

Señor Developer at Jungle Scout

Summary

Josh is based out of Vancouver BC and is part of the core team of developers that built Jungle Scout, the industry-leading Amazon product research tool helping tens of thousands of people find profitable products to sell on Amazon.

Experience

Señor Developer at Jungle Scout

October 2015 - Present

Full stack web developer focusing primarily on backend development, application and database architecture.

Ruby on Rails Developer

November 2013 - October 2015 (1 year 11 months)

- Experience working with large corporations and startups.
- Passionate about style and design.
- Ability to lead and manage projects from design to deployment.
- Develop Ruby on Rails applications with automated tests using TDD and RSpec.
- Create API's for Android, iOS applications and 3rd party applications.
- Create responsive front end designs.
- Experience deploying web applications in production using cloud platforms such as Heroku and AWS.
- Comfortable using version control system such as git and coordinating development, configuration and deployments in a team.

Senior Technical Principal Analyst at Oracle

August 2009 - May 2013 (3 years 9 months)

Provided leadership, managed, and motivated an experienced team of Application and Database Engineers to aggressively build high performance, multi-tenant hosted information solutions that are globally accessible over the web.

Configured and supported Oracle CRM On Demand to ensure 24x7 availability of all production and test environments.

Lead escalation manager that was responsible for global production service and system availability, coordinating with various teams including Engineering, GIT, Customer Care and Support to ensure all production issues were solved quickly and effectively.

Senior Systems Configuration Specialist at IBM

February 2004 - August 2009 (5 years 6 months)

Maintained hardware and software test environments for IBM Maximo builds on various virtual images, operating systems, web servers and database servers.

Senior Quality Analyst at Oracle

2000 - 2004 (4 years)

Worked on the Siebel CRM OnDemand application from its earliest conceptual stages until it was released and deployed in a multi-tenant hosted environment using techniques such as regression, integration, load, and automation.

Education

Humber College

Computer Engineering, Computer Engineering, 1997 - 2000

CodeCore Developer Bootcamp

Web Development, Ruby on Rails, 2014 - 2014

Activities and Societies: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Postgres, Rspec, API's.

CodeCore

JavaScript, 2014 - 2014

Activities and Societies: JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX

Honors and Awards

Top Performer Recognition

Josh Davies

Señor Developer at Jungle Scout



Contact Josh on LinkedIn